<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Blog EN</title>
	<atom:link href="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 Jun 2014 21:25:44 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=3.4</generator>
		<item>
		<title>PrestaShop 1.6.0.7 is Now Available to Update</title>
		<link>http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/prestashop-1-6-0-7-is-now-available-to-update/</link>
		<comments>http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/prestashop-1-6-0-7-is-now-available-to-update/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 17 Jun 2014 17:29:50 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Benjamin Utterback</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[PrestaShop News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=17560</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Hello PrestaShop Community! The latest update to 1.6 is here! 1.6.0.7 is now released with more awesomeness. We didn’t forget to squash some bugs and clean up. Here are the main improvements in this update. &#160; Improved cart summary and &#8230; <a href="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/prestashop-1-6-0-7-is-now-available-to-update/" rel="nofollow" class="more-link">Read more<span class="meta-nav"></span></a>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img style="border: 0pt none; float: left; padding-right: 10px; padding-bottom: 10px;" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/02/prestashop_1-6.png" alt="" />Hello PrestaShop Community!</p>
<p><a href="http://www.prestashop.com/en/download"><strong>The latest update to 1.6 is here!</strong></a> 1.6.0.7 is now released with more awesomeness. We didn’t forget to squash some bugs and clean up.</p>
<p>Here are the main improvements in this update.</p>
<p><span id="more-17560"></span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<ul>
<li>Improved cart summary and management with several pages + responsiveness</li>
<li>One Page Checkout fixes issue with customer messages</li>
<li>You can now add more than 8 images for a product!</li>
<li>For added security, a warning highlights the installation of a module that is not certified by Addons</li>
<li>Better Cache management throughout the Back and Front Office</li>
<li>We optimized the Dashboard for even stronger accuracy for visitors and orders</li>
<li>Now, all variations are imported when a new theme is added</li>
<li>Better CMS management with bullet points.</li>
<li>Shipping and Carrier fixes for overlapping ranges</li>
<li>Better Product OnBoarding – Theme, Shipping, and Payment pages</li>
<li>Fix of the reduction display for a pre-tax group</li>
<li>Drag &amp; Drop fix for attributes’ order</li>
<li>Fix of new supplier creation form</li>
<li>All the contact details entered in the BO are now correctly displayed in the FO, under Contact details and stores</li>
</ul>
<p>You can <a href="http://www.prestashop.com/en/developers-versions/changelog/1.6.0.7">view the entire Changelog here</a>.</p>
<p>You know we love your feedback. If you have an issue, we want to know about it.</p>
<ul>
<li>Found a bug or issues?  <a href="http://www.prestashop.com/forums/">– Search it on the Forum</a> and <a href="forge.prestashop.com">Report it to the Forge</a></li>
<li>You know how to fix an issue? - <a href="https://github.com/PrestaShop/">Submit the fix to GitHub</a></li>
<li>Found a wrong translation? - <a href="https://crowdin.net/project/prestashop-official">Fix it on Crowdin</a></li>
</ul>
<p>We would like to thank everybody who helped us with this update. The PrestaShop community is simply great, the best! Nearly 200 bugs and issues were fixed with your help, making this version the strongest PrestaShop yet! Be sure to always <a href="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/set-up-a-test-server-for-your-online-store/">backup and test your upgrades</a> before upgrading your live store.</p>
<p>That’s it for now, <a href="http://www.prestashop.com/en/download">download PrestaShop 1.6 today</a>! Stay tuned for some more exciting news coming soon!</p>
<p>Happy Selling!</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/prestashop-1-6-0-7-is-now-available-to-update/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ecommerce Success Story – An up close look at WishTrend’s tripling growth</title>
		<link>http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/ecommerce-success-story-an-up-close-look-at-wishtrends-tripling-growth/</link>
		<comments>http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/ecommerce-success-story-an-up-close-look-at-wishtrends-tripling-growth/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 10 Jun 2014 14:23:35 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Julie Liu</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Success Stories]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=17495</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[WishTrend is a Seoul based PrestaShop store and an international retailer for Korean beauty products. In a country brimming with cosmetics, only a few major brands ever gain global exposure. Eddie and Ryan, cofounders of this online store, aimed to &#8230; <a href="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/ecommerce-success-story-an-up-close-look-at-wishtrends-tripling-growth/" rel="nofollow" class="more-link">Read more<span class="meta-nav"></span></a>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://bit.ly/WishTrend" target="_blank">WishTrend</a> is a Seoul based PrestaShop store and an international retailer for Korean beauty products. In a country brimming with cosmetics, only a few major brands ever gain global exposure. Eddie and Ryan, cofounders of this online store, aimed to share “Real Korean Beauty [products]” with the world. Since launching in late 2011, they shipped more than 60% of their 700+ products to international customers in the United States, Canada and Australia.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-17497" style="color: #333333; font-style: normal; line-height: 24.375px; margin-top: 0.4em;" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/06/wish-trend-main.png" alt="" width="580" height="250" /></p>
<p>In 3 short years, this online store has successfully given 50+ local Korean beauty manufacturers international exposure. More impressively, they’ve maintained their tripling growth. Check out their success story and get inspired for yours!</p>
<p><span id="more-17495"></span></p>
<h4><span style="color: #8a2be2;">Why did you choose to open an online store?</span></h4>
<p>Korea has countless cosmetics brands with some of the greatest beauty manufacturers. Our goal is to link global consumers with underrepresented manufacturers from Korea’s cosmetics industry. We chose to open an online store because ecommerce is the easiest way to sell globally. We can communicate with our customers no matter where they are in the world. Also, we can easily update inventory and set up localized payment methods.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-17499" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/06/youtube.png" alt="" width="380" height="307" /></p>
<h4><span style="color: #8a2be2;">After your launch, what strategies did you use to drive traffic?</span></h4>
<p>First, we attempted to drive organic traffic by improving our SEO. With PrestaShop’s built in features, we easily added Meta titles, descriptions and tags then rewrote our URL’s. We then drove traffic with a strong social media presence on Facebook, YouTube, <a href="http://j.mp/PSWishTrendTwitter" target="_blank">Twitter</a>, <a href="http://j.mp/PSWishTrendPinterest" target="_blank">Pinterest</a>, and our “WishTrend Glam” blog. The most effective platforms are<a href="http://j.mp/PSWishTrendFacebook" target="_blank"> Facebook</a> (with over 61,000 likes), <a href="http://j.mp/PSWishTrendYoutube" target="_blank">YouTube</a> (with over 35,000 subscribers and 1 million views) and our blog, <a href="http://j.mp/PSWishTrendBlog" target="_blank">WishTrend Glam.</a> They all work together to increase qualified traffic to our website.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-17496" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/06/REVIEWS.png" alt="" width="445" height="217" /></p>
<h4><span style="color: #8a2be2;">Once customers land on your site, how did you convert them?</span></h4>
<p>We offer customers incentives to make purchases such as free shipping or $5 gift certificates. We then reassure visitors by displaying customer written product reviews on the home page. By leveraging both strategies, we quickly converted visitors into customers.</p>
<h4><span style="color: #8a2be2;">What about customer retention &#8211; how did you keep customers coming back?</span></h4>
<p>We send weekly newsletters to our members. In addition, we try to send customized messages to customers based on their purchase history, location and age group to provide personalized product suggestions. This extra effort helps us convert customers again and again.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-17498" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/06/YOTPO-REVIEWS.png" alt="" width="524" height="318" /></p>
<h4><span style="color: #8a2be2;">Do you use PrestaShop Modules? Which would you recommend?</span></h4>
<p>We currently use the basic <a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/en/social-commerce-facebook-prestashop-modules/7366-yotpo-social-reviews.html" target="_blank">Yotpo module </a>for product reviews. With this module, customers receive an email 15 days after making a purchase asking them to leave a review for products in their order. As an incentive, customers are offered a discount coupon for a future order. We highly recommend this module to other PrestaShop merchants.</p>
<div>
<hr align="left" size="2" width="20%" />
</div>
<p>Interested in running your own online store? <a href="http://www.prestashop.com/en/download" target="_blank">Download</a> PrestaShop today or try our <a href="http://www.prestashop.com/en/demo" target="_blank">demo</a> to experience the PrestaShop software. Take the first step to becoming the next PrestaShop ecommerce success story!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/ecommerce-success-story-an-up-close-look-at-wishtrends-tripling-growth/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Selling on Marketplaces: how to centralize your ecommerce inventory</title>
		<link>http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/selling-on-marketplaces-how-to-centralize-your-ecommerce-inventory/</link>
		<comments>http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/selling-on-marketplaces-how-to-centralize-your-ecommerce-inventory/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 10 Jun 2014 10:26:32 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Deborah Penna</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[PrestaShop Partners]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=17528</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[In this day and age, selling on e-marketplaces has become relatively indispensable for small to large ecommerce business owners. Building an online presence on European platforms such as eBay, Amazon, Rakuten, Zalando or la Redoute, just to name a few, &#8230; <a href="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/selling-on-marketplaces-how-to-centralize-your-ecommerce-inventory/" rel="nofollow" class="more-link">Read more<span class="meta-nav"></span></a>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In this day and age, selling on e-marketplaces has become relatively indispensable for small to large ecommerce business owners.</p>
<p>Building an online presence on European platforms such as eBay, Amazon, Rakuten, Zalando or la Redoute, just to name a few, can really <strong>give your business the boost it needs to grow</strong> and gain exposure to a large number of potential buyers.</p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-17531" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/06/Image7.jpg" alt="" width="520" height="289" /></p>
<p><span id="more-17528"></span></p>
<h2><span style="color: #3366ff">Why sell on marketplaces</span></h2>
<p>The most obvious reason for choosing to sell on marketplaces is that every month, these websites <strong>attract millions of online shoppers</strong> &#8211; realistically speaking, a lot more than you will ever attract to your website. In 2013, Amazon reported <strong>237 million active buyers</strong> worldwide.</p>
<p>Therefore, it makes perfect sense to <strong>link your online store to key marketplaces</strong> and start <strong>reaping the benefits</strong>, which include:</p>
<p>- making your product available to customers in different demographics &#8211; <strong>international    exposure</strong><br />
- <strong>increased level of trust by the buyer</strong>, who is familiar with the marketplace and feels  safe<br />
- security and <strong>fraud protection</strong> offered by the major e-marketplaces<br />
- <strong>marketing benefits</strong>: eBay and Amazon spend millions in driving new customers to their  websites, as mentioned by <a href="http://www.is4profit.com/get-britain-growing/trading-online/how-to-sell-successfully-on-ebay.html" target="_blank">is4profit.</a></p>
<p>Emarketplaces charge a fee to be able to use their services. However, when calculating the cost of acquiring a new customer versus paying a marketplace fee &#8211; it is worth the investment. Learn how to calculate your <a href="http://blog.hubspot.com/ecommerce/calculating-ecommerce-cost-of-customer-acquisition" target="_blank">Cost of Customer Acquisition/ CoCA here</a>.</p>
<h2><span style="color: #3366ff">How to centralize your inventory</span></h2>
<p>If you have decided to sell or are already selling on multiple platforms, <strong>it is fundamental to have a system that will help you easily manage the availability of stock</strong> and gain visibility, across all channels. If, for example, a product sells out on eBay, as a store owner you should know &#8211; in real time &#8211; whether or not, that same product might be available on an another channel. Synchronisation of your inventory levels and order fulfillment, therefore, plays a major role.</p>
<p>Simply by installing a centralised system that will let you list, synchronise and distribute your stock across the various platforms, will allow you to streamline your operations, improve your overall inventory management and handle your entire sales cycle more effectively. One system to manage it all.</p>
<p><img class="size-full wp-image-17530 aligncenter" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/06/Marketplaces-image.jpg" alt="" width="619" height="245" /></p>
<h3><span style="color: #3366ff">Neteven &#8211; European Marketplace Management</span></h3>
<p>With over 8 years’ experience in working closely with the major marketplaces in Europe, Neteven has become the leading provider of Marketplace Management solutions.</p>
<p><img class="size-full wp-image-17529 aligncenter" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/06/logo-neteven.jpg" alt="" width="215" height="80" /></p>
<p>In order to make it simple for you to sell more efficiently, and <strong>distribute your catalogue across the major European platforms at a click of a mouse</strong>, a marketplace management module has been developed for PrestaShop users.</p>
<p>The module includes the following functionalities:</p>
<p>- Inventory management<br />
- Attributes and variations management<br />
- Bar codes publishing<br />
- Rich media product creation<br />
- Automated listing<br />
- Stock automation<br />
- Repricing<br />
- Optimization tools<br />
- End of transactions<br />
- Reporting tool</p>
<p>Synchronise your PrestaShop catalogue with Neteven and manage all your inventory from a single interface.</p>
<p>The <a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/en/marketplace-prestashop-modules/8091-neteven.html">Neteven module</a> is native in the software and it’s compatible with v.1.4.01 &#8211; v1.6.0.6. It is also available for download, free of charge, on <strong>PrestaShop’s Official Marketplace</strong>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/selling-on-marketplaces-how-to-centralize-your-ecommerce-inventory/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Benefits of offering your products in your customer’s local currency</title>
		<link>http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/benefits-of-offering-your-products-in-your-customers-local-currency/</link>
		<comments>http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/benefits-of-offering-your-products-in-your-customers-local-currency/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 04 Jun 2014 15:46:56 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Julie Liu</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[PrestaShop Partners]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=17470</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[You started your online business to broaden your customer base. Because of this, you’re shipping orders all around the world, even to places you’ve never visited. All of this is very exciting but now you’re hearing terms like “localization”, “internationalization” &#8230; <a href="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/benefits-of-offering-your-products-in-your-customers-local-currency/" rel="nofollow" class="more-link">Read more<span class="meta-nav"></span></a>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>You started your online business to broaden your customer base. Because of this, you’re shipping orders all around the world, even to places you’ve never visited. All of this is very exciting but now you’re hearing terms like “localization”, “internationalization” and “multi-currency.” Do you know everything you need to know to run a business for your international customer base? Should you consider localizing and accepting payments in your customers’ local currency? We’re here to demystify and explain why you should and the best way to offer multiple currencies in your shopping cart!<br />
<img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-17471" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/06/EN-Benefits-of-offering-your-products.jpg" alt="" width="580" height="248" /></p>
<p><span id="more-17470"></span>The importance of supporting multiple currencies is best explained with the pitfalls of single currency checkouts. Enabling only one currency for your shopping cart not only limits your customers to <strong>shop </strong>but also <strong>checkout </strong>using that currency. This could be a major deal breaker for a customer who can’t find their local currency.</p>
<h4><span style="color: #993300;">Pitfalls of single currency checkouts</span></h4>
<p>Limiting customers to shop in a foreign currency deters them from completing purchases and leads to cart abandonment and lost sales. According to <a href="http://www.statista.com/statistics/232285/reasons-for-online-shopping-cart-abandonment/" target="_blank">Statista</a>, 13% of online shoppers abandon a site when prices are presented in a foreign currency. . Additionally, once a customer makes a purchase in a foreign currency, their banks may impose foreign transaction fees; thus penalizing your customers for shopping on your online store.</p>
<h4><span style="color: #993300;">Offer Multiple Currencies with Authorize.Net</span></h4>
<p>That’s where <a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/en/payments-gateways-prestashop-modules/4154-authorizenet-aim.html" target="_blank">Authorize.Net</a> &#8211; a PrestaShop certified multiple-currency payment processor and a pioneering provider of ecommerce payment services &#8211; can help. Authorize.Net supports multiple currencies (USD, GBP, EUROS, AUD, CAD, NZD), so by using Authorize.Net and PrestaShop together, you may increase sales by allowing customers to shop and checkout in their local currency. Avoid chasing customers away with foreign bank fees and fluctuating exchange rates! Learn more by visiting PrestaShop Addons, and get started by downloading the Authorize.Net module.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-17486" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/06/147-1.png" alt="" width="220" height="127" /></p>
<p>In addition to accepting payments in multiple currencies, PrestaShop merchants using <a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/en/payments-gateways-prestashop-modules/4154-authorizenet-aim.html" target="_blank">Authorize.Net</a> also enjoy the following great benefits:</p>
<ol>
<ul>
<li>Free Customer Support</li>
<li>Free Virtual Terminal</li>
<li>Easy Set Up and Configuration</li>
<li>Additional Services Including:
<ol>
<ul>
<li>Recurring Billing</li>
<li>Payment Tokenization</li>
<li>Advanced Fraud Detection</li>
</ul>
</ol>
</li>
<li>No Long Term Commitments</li>
</ul>
</ol>
<div>
<hr align="left" size="2" width="20%" />
</div>
<p>Not yet a PrestaShop merchant? What are you waiting for? <a href="http://www.prestashop.com/en/download" target="_blank">Download </a>the best ecommerce software to start selling to customers abroad in their preferred, local currency and watch your business become an international sensation.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/benefits-of-offering-your-products-in-your-customers-local-currency/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Join PrestaShop and the biggest names in Ecommerce at IRCE 2014</title>
		<link>http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/join-prestashop-and-biggest-names-in-ecommerce-at-irce-2014/</link>
		<comments>http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/join-prestashop-and-biggest-names-in-ecommerce-at-irce-2014/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2014 13:17:36 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Julie Liu</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Events]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=17427</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Since opening our Miami office in 2011, we kick off each summer with a trip to the windy city for the annual Internet Retailer Conference and Exhibition (IRCE). This year, we’re happy to celebrate the 10th anniversary of the World’s &#8230; <a href="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/join-prestashop-and-biggest-names-in-ecommerce-at-irce-2014/" rel="nofollow" class="more-link">Read more<span class="meta-nav"></span></a>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Since opening our Miami office in 2011, we kick off each summer with a trip to the windy city for the annual <span style="color: #0066cc">Internet Retailer Conference and Exhibition</span> (<a href="http://www.irce.com/" target="_blank">IRCE</a>). This year, we’re happy to celebrate the 10th anniversary of the World’s Largest Ecommerce event. With a projected attendance of over 10,000 ecommerce enthusiasts, we can’t wait to see what this year’s conference brings.</p>
<p style="text-align: center"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-17437" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/06/irce.png" alt="" width="253" height="168" /></p>
<p><span id="more-17427"></span>From <strong><span style="color: #0066cc">June 10th &#8211; 12th</span></strong>, join the PrestaShop Team in Chicago to rub elbows with some of the biggest names in ecommerce. Gain experience by hearing from speakers from ecommerce giants like Zuilly, Dermalogica, and Gilt Group. Or, check out solution partners that can help you grow your online store.</p>
<p>Stop by our<span style="color: #0066cc"><strong> booth #443</strong></span> to learn more about PrestaShop v1.6, test live demos or just to meet the PrestaShop team. Don’t forget to pick up your very own PrestaShop T-shirt, speakers sponsored by <a href="https://secure1.inmotionhosting.com/cgi-bin/gby/clickthru.cgi?id=prestashop&amp;campaign=endownload&amp;page=336" target="_blank">InMotion Hosting</a> and other goodies. Follow us on <a href="https://twitter.com/prestashop" target="_blank">Twitter </a>for live updates from the event and Tweet at us if you’re also attending.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.xpressreg.net/register/irce064/attendee/landing.asp?sc=&amp;aban=&amp;hkey=&amp;iq=&amp;tm=&amp;__utma=1.1065534104.1401284095.1401292054.1401305610.3&amp;__utmb=1.4.10.1401305610&amp;__utmc=1&amp;__utmx=-&amp;__utmz=1.1401292054.2.2.utmcsr=google|utmccn=(organic)|utmcmd=organic|utmctr=(not%20provided)&amp;__utmv=-&amp;__utmk=17735353" target="_blank">Register today</a>; we hope to see you there.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/join-prestashop-and-biggest-names-in-ecommerce-at-irce-2014/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>How to manage Sales Taxes on your Online Store</title>
		<link>http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/how-to-manage-sales-taxes-on-your-online-store/</link>
		<comments>http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/how-to-manage-sales-taxes-on-your-online-store/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2014 09:21:47 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Deborah Penna</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[PrestaShop Partners]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=17442</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[When setting up an online store, more often than not, people tend to overlook or consider sales tax requirements, somewhat late in the process. However, it’s imperative for online retailers to get familiar with the local regulations, in a timely &#8230; <a href="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/how-to-manage-sales-taxes-on-your-online-store/" rel="nofollow" class="more-link">Read more<span class="meta-nav"></span></a>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>When setting up an online store, more often than not, people tend to overlook or consider sales tax requirements, somewhat late in the process. However, it’s imperative for online retailers to get familiar with the local regulations, in a timely manner.</p>
<p>And if your online store is already fully functional, then you might want to make sure that you’re handling your sales taxes the right way.</p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-17444" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/06/Money_image1.jpg" alt="" width="520" height="175" /></p>
<p><span id="more-17442"></span></p>
<p>Simply put, <strong>sales taxes will impact your overall business revenues</strong> and should be carefully studied, from the beginning. In this article, we’ll cover some of the basics concepts that you should be aware of. However, the laws and regulations change in each country and a qualified person should be consulted.</p>
<h2>Selling locally and collecting sales taxes online</h2>
<p>When selling locally, within your state or country, the computation of sales taxes should be, mostly, quite straightforward. In this case, you pass the costs on to your customers. In other words, you charge your customers the due sales tax, upon making a purchase &#8211; at checkout. However, <strong>how do you know ‘if’ and ‘how much sales tax’, you should charge your customers</strong>, when you sell outside your business jurisdiction or abroad?</p>
<h2>US Online Merchants</h2>
<p>According to the current law, if you have a physical presence in a State (also known as ‘nexus’), i.e. a brick-and-mortar store, you are required to charge your customers, the applicable local sales tax rate. If, however, you do not have a physical presence in a specific State, you are not required to collect taxes. The <a href="http://www.sba.gov/content/collecting-sales-tax-over-internet" target="_blank">Supreme Court ruling</a> in 1992, affirms that catalog and, by extension, online retailers are only required to collect taxes in the States where they have an actual physical presence.</p>
<p>However, under the <strong>Market Fairness Act (2013)</strong>, things could change. If the current legislation passed into law, online merchants would be required to pay sales tax, just as any other business. According to this legislation, each State would be entitled to collect sales taxes from remote sellers.<br />
You can consult the applicable sales tax law in your State, <a href="http://www.nolo.com/legal-encyclopedia/50-state-guide-internet-sales-tax-laws.html" target="_blank">here</a>.</p>
<h2>European Online Merchants</h2>
<p>The <a href="http://ec.europa.eu/taxation_customs/taxation/vat/how_vat_works/distance_selling/index_en.htm" target="_blank">EU</a> defines ‘distance selling’ as: ‘a supplier that sells goods to private individuals or customers established in another Member State who do not apply VAT to their intra-Community acquisition of goods’.<br />
Within the EU, the ‘VAT of the Member State of destination’ is applied and must be collected, in that Member State, if sales exceed a certain threshold &#8211; €100,000 or 35,000 or the equivalent in national currency. To find out more about each country’s threshold, see the Commission’s information document &#8211; <a href="http://ec.europa.eu/taxation_customs/resources/documents/taxation/vat/traders/vat_community/vat_in_ec_annexi.pdf" target="_blank">Thresholds &#8211; Annex I</a>.</p>
<h2>Canadian Online Merchants</h2>
<p>The Canadian sales tax system is still divided. This means that different sales tax rates are applicable and vary in each province. Generally, when you sell and deliver goods to another province, your customer’s location determines the percentage of tax you should collect. And if you sell goods abroad, outside of Canada, you are not required to collect GST/HST and PST, according to the Canada Business Network’s guide, which you can find <a href="http://www.canadabusiness.ca/eng/page/2651/" target="_blank">here</a>.</p>
<h3>Let Avalara help you out with Sales Tax Compliance!</h3>
<p>Accurately calculating, collecting and remitting sales taxes is no easy task. <strong>Avalara helps businesses of all sizes to become compliant and manage sales tax</strong>, rapidly and easily. They will do all the necessary research on your behalf and automate the process, ensuring the system is up-to-date with the most recent sales tax and VAT rates and regulations.</p>
<p><img class="size-full wp-image-17443 aligncenter" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/06/Avalara-Logo-CMYK-2.jpg" alt="" width="267" height="129" /></p>
<p>Thanks to AvaTax &#8211; Avalara’s certified module for PrestaShop, you will be able to benefit from the following features:</p>
<p>- Address Validation included<br />
- Rooftop Accurate Calculations<br />
- Product and Service Taxability Rules<br />
- Out-of-the-Box Sales Tax Reporting<br />
- And, the filing can be done for you!</p>
<p><a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/en/billing-invoicing-prestashop-modules/5040-avalara-avatax.html" target="_blank">Avalara’s module</a> is available native in the software or can be downloaded, for free, via <strong>PrestaShop’s Official Marketplace</strong>. It is compatible with PrestaShop v1.4.0.1 to v1.6.0.6.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/how-to-manage-sales-taxes-on-your-online-store/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>10 Things I Wish I Knew Before Opening an Ecommerce Site</title>
		<link>http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/10-things-i-wish-i-knew-before-opening-an-ecommerce-site/</link>
		<comments>http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/10-things-i-wish-i-knew-before-opening-an-ecommerce-site/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2014 15:55:02 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Julie Liu</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Tips and Advice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=17389</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[You’re just about ready to launch your online store – you have your products and website ready to go – so what could you possibly be missing? We asked online merchants what ideas and concepts they didn’t understand until after &#8230; <a href="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/10-things-i-wish-i-knew-before-opening-an-ecommerce-site/" rel="nofollow" class="more-link">Read more<span class="meta-nav"></span></a>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>You’re just about ready to launch your online store – you have your products and website ready to go – so what could you possibly be missing? We asked online merchants what ideas and concepts they didn’t understand until after they opened their online store and we got some interesting responses.</p>
<p>They say hindsight is 20/20 vision, so let’s learn from the experiences of successful online retailers who share: the 10 things I wish I knew before opening an ecommerce site.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-17407" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/05/en10thingsiwishiknew.jpg" alt="" width="576" height="245" /></p>
<p><span id="more-17389"></span></p>
<h4><span style="color: #428ea5;"><em><strong><br />
</strong></em></span></h4>
<blockquote>
<h4><span style="color: #428ea5;"><strong><strong>1)</strong> &#8221;Business plans are not just for business students.”</strong></span></h4>
</blockquote>
<p>Have a well thought out business plan. Sounds cliché but true. It’s easy to think that your online business will just play out but a <strong>detailed business plan is your ticket to success</strong>. It should cover everything you need to plan, strategize and launch your online store. A business plan will also make you ask yourself questions that you may not have thought of before. Plan for a successful online store with these <a href="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/how-to-create-an-online-store-10-steps-to-write-your-business-plan/" target="_blank">10 steps to write your ecommerce business plan.</a></p>
<blockquote>
<h4><span style="color: #428ea5;"><strong>2) “Know your business well but know your competitors better.”</strong></span></h4>
</blockquote>
<p>Have an in-depth understanding of similar products and services available to customers. Consider businesses that do what you do but also those that can take can replace your business. Once you pinpoint your competitors, <strong>learn everything you can about them</strong>, such as:</p>
<ol>
<li>Where do they advertise?</li>
<li>How do they handle customer service?</li>
<li>What features does their site have?</li>
<li>How do they price their products?</li>
<li>How is their site better? How is yours?</li>
</ol>
<p>Also, gauge your competitors’ marketing efforts. One of the greatest tools recommended by a store owner is <a href="http://www.semrush.com/" target="_blank">SEMRush</a>, which provides full reports on a company’s SEM and SEO efforts.</p>
<blockquote>
<h4><span style="color: #428ea5;"><strong>3) “SEO is not just another acronym.”</strong></span></h4>
</blockquote>
<p>Understand the importance of SEO (search engine optimization) from the get-go. As you just saw above, <strong>search engine optimization is essentially the lifeline of your online business</strong>. Be familiar with SEO best practices before you or your developer start your SEO efforts.</p>
<p>The following articles will help give you a clear understanding of SEO and how it can help your ecommerce site:</p>
<ol>
<ul>
<li><a href="http://blog.kissmetrics.com/seo-for-ecommerce-websites/" target="_blank">The Ultimate Guide to SEO for E-commerce Websites</a> by Kiss Metrics</li>
<li><a href="http://moz.com/blog/perfecting-onpage-optimization-for-ecommerce-websites" target="_blank"> Perfecting On-Page Optimization for Ecommerce Websites </a>by Moz</li>
<li><a href="http://www.webseoanalytics.com/blog/60-seo-tips-online-marketing-techniques-for-ecommerce-websites/" target="_blank">60 SEO Tips and Online Marketing Techniques for Ecommerce Websites </a>by WebSEO Analytics</li>
</ul>
</ol>
<p>Something many merchants also wish they knew is that Google frequently change their rules. Make sure you’re always up to date on best practices by signing up for <a href="https://www.google.com/webmasters/tools/home?hl=en" target="_blank">Google’s Webmaster Tools</a>.<em> </em></p>
<blockquote>
<h4><span style="color: #428ea5;"><strong>4) “Defrauders live in our world, too.”</strong></span></h4>
</blockquote>
<p>Once you start selling online, you open up your “digital” doors to all types of people from all types of places. Just because you operate by certain a moral code does not mean everyone else does too. <strong>Be aware of people, namely defrauders, who operate unethically.</strong> Some examples of situations merchants found themselves facing include:</p>
<ol>
<ul>
<li>Charge backs from unauthorized credit card use</li>
<li>Damaged and undelivered package claims</li>
<li>Customers returning goods in used condition</li>
<li>Hackers looking to steal customer information</li>
</ul>
</ol>
<p>To prevent credit card chargebacks, be vigilant in spotting <a href="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/canada-7-tips-on-fraud-and-risk-control-for-ecommerce/" target="_blank">characteristics of “card not present” fraud</a>. Large purchases, multiple purchases at a single time, and the sale of an item from a low traffic page are just a few examples. Keep in mind that as you set up roadblocks to prevent fraudulent activity, you make it harder for normal customers to make purchases. For example, secure passwords that keep out hackers – 8 characters long with a number, letter, and symbol – may also keep out customers.</p>
<blockquote>
<h4><span style="color: #428ea5;"><strong>5) “Walk a mile in your customers&#8217; shoes.”</strong></span></h4>
</blockquote>
<p>It’s easy to get caught up in seeing things from your perspective. But when you start to consider any decision about your online store, be sure to think about the effect it will have on your customer. <a href="http://www.forbes.com/sites/groupthink/2013/07/03/online-personas-the-key-to-converting-customers/" target="_blank">Create a persona</a>, give them a name, and always consider what they think.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">For example, to provide better personalized newsletters, a merchant required customers to fill in more information about themselves. Instead of learning more about customers, they drove them away. Once customers saw the number of required fields and the amount of private information they had to share, they simply abandoned the cart.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">Another merchant decided to offset increased shipping costs by removing their shipping special. Customers now have to pay for shipping regardless of their purchase total. Although they expected a small drop in in orders, they did not expect the average order value to drop as well. They successfully offset shipping costs but ultimately lost revenue from decreased order totals.</p>
<p>Bottom line: <strong>Always consider how your decisions will affect your customer. </strong><em><br />
</em></p>
<blockquote>
<h4><span style="color: #428ea5;"><strong>6) “Don’t underestimate the power of a personal touch.”</strong></span></h4>
</blockquote>
<p>Selling through a digital storefront makes it easy to forget that <strong>customers are people</strong> &#8211; real, live human beings. The world of ecommerce can feel impersonal but that’s easy to change by adding a personal touch. It is a way to separate yourself from giant online stores like Amazon. Adding a personal touch may seem counterproductive because of the amount of time you spend, but it can go a long way.</p>
<p>Some merchants surprise customers with small gifts with each order. They don’t use it as a marketing ploy or a sales tactic but just a way of saying “thanks” for their patronage. These simple gestures keep customers coming back time and time again. This adds to the bottom line by saving countless dollars that would have otherwise been spent on acquiring new customers.</p>
<blockquote>
<h4><span style="color: #428ea5;"><strong>7) “Listen.”</strong></span></h4>
</blockquote>
<p>It is a simple concept but the challenge lies in its execution. Whether it is to your customer, your developer or your team, it’s important <strong>to take time to listen to what they have to say</strong>. When you’re providing customer service, take time to understand your customers’ problems. If you are unable to paraphrase your customers’ problem, you do not fully understand their issue. Taking time to listen will not only help you provide better service but lead to increased customer loyalty. You should also <a href="http://www.fatlabwebsupport.com/blog/listen-web-developer-flexible-better-product/" target="_blank">listen to your development team</a>. It not only creates a good working relationship but speeds up the development process. Regardless of who you listen to, be sure to take it with a grain of salt. Understand their perspective and where their ideas/concerns stem from. Are they saying it to help improve your product/online store, or are they being lazy?<em> </em></p>
<blockquote>
<h4><span style="color: #428ea5;"><strong>8) “You are as strong as your weakest link.”</strong></span></h4>
</blockquote>
<p>Running a successful online store usually involves small teams of people. Your team is anyone who helped you get your online store ready for launch. This includes everyone from the photographer, to the developer and even your investor. The weakest link in your company isn’t necessarily the person who contributes the least or works the fewest amount of hours. It is the person who has a negative attitude. I don’t mean to start a crusade against anyone who has a bad day, because we all have those. Just be sure to take note of <strong>anyone who doesn’t believe in your product or service </strong>and brings down the company morale. Keep in mind that you are also part of the team and your morale matters. Try out these tips from <a href="http://www.smallbusinesscomputing.com/tipsforsmallbusiness/hire-positive-people-to-build-a-thriving-business.html" target="_blank">Small Business Computing</a>, to build a positive team for your online business.<em> </em></p>
<blockquote>
<h4><span style="color: #428ea5;"><strong>9) “Done is better than perfect.”</strong></span></h4>
</blockquote>
<p>In an ideal world, everything should operate like clockwork. You have quality images for your products, each product description is error free and SEO friendly, and your web site has a beautiful responsive design &#8211; down to the last pixel. However, in the real world, this is hardly ever the case. Problems come up and things don’t always go your way. As one merchant shares, learn early on that not everything has to be perfect. Simple product descriptions are better than no product descriptions. The same goes for social media. Acting and reacting to posts every day brings more value than a perfectly-timed and fancy social media campaigns. <strong>By settling for good enough, you get more done </strong>which leaves you more time to perfect the things that do matter. Is your site good enough? Ensure you have these <a href="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/the-top-10-things-customers-are-looking-for-on-your-e-commerce-site/" target="_blank">10 things customers look for on your ecommerce site</a>.<em> </em></p>
<blockquote>
<h4><span style="color: #428ea5;"><strong>10) “For every beginning, there is an ending.”</strong></span></h4>
</blockquote>
<p>It’s tough to think about the end of your business just as you are starting up, but having a concrete exit strategy is important. Sure the exit strategy should be part of your business plan, but we’re showing you how important it is by including here again. The chance that you’ll pass down the business to your child, if they even want it, is very unlikely. The following piece of advice helped one merchant come to terms with the need for an exit strategy.</p>
<p><strong>You are not the online business but rather an employee of the business. </strong>As an employee, what you invest into the company should be returned to you as the company starts making money. Whether you choose to run your business forever or sell it to someone, an exit strategy will help you see the bigger picture. When it comes to making important decisions, it will help you see past this week’s profits to make choices that will benefit you in the long run.</p>
<p>Check out some examples of exit strategies from <a href="http://www.entrepreneur.com/article/78512" target="_blank">Entrepreneur</a>. Then figure out which one is the best for you with this article from <a href="http://www.inc.com/guides/2010/10/how-to-choose-an-exit-strategy.html" target="_blank">INC Magazine</a>.</p>
<p>What advice will you take to heart? If you already own your online store, what advice would you share with new merchants? Tell us your stories in the comments below.</p>
<div>
<hr align="left" size="2" width="20%" />
</div>
<p>Now that you’re wiser, get ready to open your very own online store. Learn more about PrestaShop by testing our <a href="http://www.prestashop.com/en/demo" target="_blank">demo </a>or <a href="http://www.prestashop.com/en/download" target="_blank">download </a>the software to get started today!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/10-things-i-wish-i-knew-before-opening-an-ecommerce-site/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>7 Strategies to Implement When Your Website Traffic Drops</title>
		<link>http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/7-strategies-to-implement-when-your-website-traffic-drops/</link>
		<comments>http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/7-strategies-to-implement-when-your-website-traffic-drops/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2014 14:53:38 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Julie Liu</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Tips and Advice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=17332</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Traffic was never an issue for you until one day &#8220;BAM!&#8221;, your site traffic drops. Your once bustling online store is quieter than a ghost town. Potential customers have suddenly disappeared and you’re left with an online store with no &#8230; <a href="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/7-strategies-to-implement-when-your-website-traffic-drops/" rel="nofollow" class="more-link">Read more<span class="meta-nav"></span></a>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Traffic was never an issue for you until one day &#8220;BAM!&#8221;, your site traffic drops. Your once bustling online store is quieter than a ghost town. Potential customers have suddenly disappeared and you’re left with an online store with no customers. Where did your traffic go? How do you get your customers back? Today we’re sharing 7 strategies to implement when your website traffic drops.</p>
<p>If you already use <a href="http://www.google.com/analytics/" target="_blank">Google Analytics</a>, you have access to demographics of your visitors. If you do not already have Google Analytics, set it up today. It provides statistics like percentage of returning vs new visitors, bounce rate and referrals source which will help you decide which strategies to implement.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-17365" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/05/en-7strategies-1.jpg" alt="" width="580" height="250" /></p>
<p><span id="more-17332"></span></p>
<h2><span style="color: #008000">1) Improve Your SEO</span></h2>
<p>If majority of your traffic originated from organic searches, Google’s new search algorithm may be penalizing your site for making one or more of these <a href="http://boostblogtraffic.com/seo-mistakes/" target="_blank">SEO mistakes</a>. After addressing one … or many of these issues, <a href="https://support.google.com/webmasters/answer/35843" target="_blank">submit a reconsideration request</a>. You can also submit your updated URL to other site engines like <a href="http://www.bing.com/toolbox/submit-site-url" target="_blank">Bing </a>and <a href="http://www.dmoz.org/docs/en/add.html" target="_blank">Dmoz </a>to increase traffic. Prepare for Google to re-index your site by updating your Meta descriptions. They should not only describe your online store but be enticing enough to draw customers in. Next, generate a new site map, which outlines the layout of your website (from the PrestaShop Back Office, Google Sitemap Module, Configure, Generate Sitemap.)</p>
<h2><span style="color: #008000">2) Drive Traffic with Social Media</span></h2>
<p>Your online store should have at least one social media account, preferably the one your target customers engage with the most. Not sure which is best? Check out these <a href="http://www.pewinternet.org/2013/02/14/the-demographics-of-social-media-users-2012/" target="_blank">demographics of social media users</a> put together by PewResearch. After setting up an account, your first order of business it to complete your profile. Your profile should include an appropriate and relevant profile picture as well as a link back to your store. Check out <a href="https://twitter.com/prestashop" target="_blank">PrestaShop’s Twitter Account</a> for an example! Be sure to contribute relevant information on a regular basis and occasionally promote your products.</p>
<p style="text-align: center"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-17333" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/05/PS-Twitter.png" alt="" width="207" height="371" /></p>
<h2><span style="color: #008000">3) Leverage Content Marketing</span></h2>
<p>Have you set up a blog for your online store? Get started by reading our previous blog post about <a title="Content Marketing for Ecommerce: Technical checklist and Writing process" href="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/content-marketing-for-ecommerce-technical-checklist-writing-process/" target="_blank">content marketing for ecommerce</a>. The important takeaway? Content marketing is a strategy that takes time and dedication. To successfully run and maintain a blog, you must write good and relevant content. Here’s a look at how content marketing drives traffic:</p>
<p style="text-align: center"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-17334" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/05/SEO.png" alt="" width="504" height="225" /></p>
<p>Already using content marketing? Here are 3 tasks to take on today.</p>
<ol>
<li><a href="https://plus.google.com/authorship" target="_blank">Set up Google+ Authorship</a> (to have an author image appear next to your article)</li>
<li>Incorporate color, images and headers tags (such as &lt;h1&gt; )</li>
<li>Use relevant keywords
<ol>
<ul>
<li>Here’s sample text for an online store selling pens:
<ol>
<li><strong>Bad</strong>: I enjoy selling products online<em> *no keywords used</em></li>
<li><strong>Very Bad</strong>: I enjoy selling pen, pens, cheap pens, blue pens, and personalized pens online.<em> *keyword stuffing</em></li>
<li><strong>Good</strong>: I enjoy selling pens online <em>*specifying with relevant keywords</em></li>
</ol>
</li>
</ul>
</ol>
</li>
</ol>
<h2><span style="color: #008000">4) Reach Out to Customers</span></h2>
<p>Email customers to get feedback about your site and suggestions for improvements. Try questions like:</p>
<ol>
<ul>
<li>“What are your first impressions of our website?”</li>
<li>“On a scale from 1-10, how would you rate your experience?”</li>
<li>“How can we improve our online store?&#8221;</li>
</ul>
</ol>
<p>For more examples check out <a href="https://www.surveymonkey.com/mp/customer-satisfaction-surveys/?ut_source=header" target="_blank">SurveyMonkey’s Customer Satisfaction Surveys</a>. Respect your customer’s time by keeping response times to 5 minutes. Focus your attention on Problems and issues that are often repeated. Also, give customers an incentive to provide feedback by offering an online gift certificate. By doing so, you also drive traffic to your online store.</p>
<h2><span style="color: #008000">5) Share Your Knowledge</span></h2>
<p>What are you a self-proclaimed expert at? What need does your online store fulfill? Think of questions potential customers may ask. Then find those customers on forums and answer their questions and suggest an appropriate product.</p>
<h4>An example for online stores:</h4>
<p><strong>Retailer: </strong>PrestaShop Jewelry Store (<a href="www.harryfay.co.uk" target="_blank">Harry Fay</a>)<br />
<strong>Sample Question:</strong> What to get my <a href="https://answers.yahoo.com/question/index?qid=20130703131455AA6ewIz" target="_blank">girlfriend for her birthday</a>?<br />
<strong>Sample Answer: </strong><br />
“Necklaces are a good choice as they&#8217;re easier for guys to choose.<br />
If she already wears necklace, get a similar one.<br />
Here are two completely different ones that I quickly found.<br />
<a href="http://www.harryfay.co.uk/necklaces-and-pendants/88-owl-baltic-amber-silver-pendant.html" target="_blank"> Owl Necklace</a><br />
<a href="http://www.harryfay.co.uk/necklaces-and-pendants/46-silver-heart-pendant-with-17-cubic-zirconias.html" target="_blank"> Heart Necklace</a><br />
Good luck. I know how difficult it is to find presents.”</p>
<h4>Also, check out how our Community Manager promoted PrestaShop for the best ecommerce solution on <a href="http://www.quora.com/Which-ecommerce-solution-is-better-for-Small-Business-owners-Volusion-Shopify-Prestashop-BigCommerce" target="_blank">Quora</a>:</h4>
<p style="text-align: center"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-17369" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/05/ecommerce-solution.png" alt="" width="478" height="507" /></p>
<h2><span style="color: #008000">6) Start a PPC (Pay Per Click) Advertising Campaign</span></h2>
<p>Run an online advertising campaign on search engine affiliated <a href="http://www.practicalecommerce.com/articles/2728-25-Advertising-Networks-for-Online-Businesses" target="_blank">advertising networks</a> like Google AdWords and Yahoo Bing Ads. Both platforms offer similar functionalities like daily max budgets, Geo location targeting and campaign analytics. Start by determining the budget for your advertising campaign. Next, create a list of keywords or terms that potential customers might search. Finally, write the copy for your ads and start your campaigns. Keep in mind that these two factors drive up the cost of your ads 1) non relevant keywords and 2) the popularity of a keyword.</p>
<p>Aside from PPC Ads, there are many other ways to advertise online. Some examples include <a href="https://www.facebook.com/advertising" target="_blank">Facebook Ads</a>, <a href="http://business.pinterest.com/en/content/webform/promoted-pins" target="_blank">Promoted Pins</a>, and even through affiliate marketing on <a href="http://www.shareasale.com/" target="_blank">ShareASale</a>.</p>
<h2><span style="color: #008000">7) Upgrade Your Online Store</span></h2>
<p>Invest in your online store to improve visitors’ user experience. Where exactly should you invest your time? Start by analyzing your site with <a href="https://developers.google.com/speed/pagespeed/insights/" target="_blank">Google’s Page Speed Insights</a>. The results give you a report with problem areas segmented by a mobile and desktop views. Address mobile/ responsive issues by upgrading to PrestaShop 1.6. If you’re not sure how to make those changes, consider hiring a <a href="http://www.prestashop.com/en/web-agency-partners" target="_blank">PrestaShop certified web developer</a>.</p>
<p style="text-align: center"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-17337" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/05/GoogleSiteSpeed.png" alt="" width="508" height="303" /></p>
<p>Other upgrades to consider include:</p>
<ol>
<ul>
<li>Upgrading hosting to increase site speed</li>
<li>Increasing your advertising budget</li>
<li>Purchasing mistyped URLs (Such as <a href="http://www.prestashop.net" target="_blank">www.PrestaShop.net</a> for <a href="http://www.prestashop.com/" target="_blank">www.PrestaShop.com</a>)</li>
</ul>
</ol>
<p>Are you experiencing a drop in your site traffic? Which of these strategies will you consider implementing? Try it out and let us know how it works!</p>
<div>
<hr align="left" size="2" width="33%" />
</div>
<p>Not an online merchant yet? <a href="http://www.prestashop.com/en/demo" target="_blank">Demo PrestaShop</a>, the best ecommerce software, to get a feel for our software or <a href="http://www.prestashop.com/en/download" target="_blank">download </a>PrestaShop and start selling online today!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/7-strategies-to-implement-when-your-website-traffic-drops/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>5</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ecommerce: must-have payment methods in Europe</title>
		<link>http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/ecommerce-must-have-payment-methods-in-europe/</link>
		<comments>http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/ecommerce-must-have-payment-methods-in-europe/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 20 May 2014 10:25:22 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Deborah Penna</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[PrestaShop Partners]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=17309</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Exciting times lie ahead: your ecommerce business is growing and you’re finally in a position to begin exploring opportunities across the border. So, how do you prepare your ecommerce business for cross-border selling? Which key elements should you consider and &#8230; <a href="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/ecommerce-must-have-payment-methods-in-europe/" rel="nofollow" class="more-link">Read more<span class="meta-nav"></span></a>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Exciting times lie ahead: your ecommerce business is growing and you’re finally in a position to begin exploring opportunities across the border.</p>
<p>So, how do you prepare your ecommerce business for cross-border selling? Which key elements should you consider and implement on your website straightaway?<img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-17319" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/05/handsglobere.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="277" /></p>
<p><span id="more-17309"></span>When it comes to online shopping there are truly no borders. Digital communities of online buyers have sprung up, looking for the best deals around the world. Representing a great opportunity for online stores, especially as global ecommerce sales are set to grow, according to recent studies by <a href="http://www.emarketer.com/Article/Global-B2C-Ecommerce-Sales-Hit-15-Trillion-This-Year-Driven-by-Growth-Emerging-Markets/1010575" target="_blank">eMarketer.com</a>.</p>
<p><img class="size-full wp-image-17311 aligncenter" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/05/Emarketer.167671_re.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="292" /></p>
<p>However, even though the internet has undoubtedly paved the way for globalization and international exposure, allowing businesses to reach a much wider audience, the phrase <strong>‘Think Global, Act Local’</strong> is more relevant today than ever before!</p>
<p><strong>Localization</strong><br />
Localization is a key aspect of cross-border selling and it should be carefully evaluated in order to convert foreign customers.</p>
<p>Three basic elements of localization should be considered:</p>
<p><strong>1- Translating your website into the language of the country you wish to target</strong><br />
New Research clearly shows that most shoppers are likely to buy a product if they can place the order in their native language, as stated by <a href="http://www.kwintessential.co.uk/read-our-blog/localization-important-for-successful-global-ecommerce.html" target="_blank">Kwintessential</a>.<br />
- 55% of the participants affirmed that they prefer to buy a product from websites providing information in their own language; this figure was as high as 80% for people who don’t speak English</p>
<p><strong>2- Displaying prices in the local currency</strong><br />
This will help buyers make a decision faster, as opposed to having to convert prices</p>
<p><strong>3- Offering local payment methods</strong><br />
This is key to convert customers. Providing the preferred local method of payment, will prevent you from losing sales to your competitors.</p>
<h2>What are the most relevant payment methods per country, in Europe?</h2>
<p>The choice of payment method varies from country to country and is strongly related to the availability of local financial services. The table below offers an overview of preferred payment options, based on a study conducted by <strong>InnoPay &#8211; “Online Payments 2012. Moving beyond the web”<strong>.</strong></strong></p>
<p><img class="size-full wp-image-17310 alignnone" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/05/HiPay-Countries.png" alt="" width="600" height="379" /></p>
<h2>HiPay Wallet: payment solutions specific to each country</h2>
<p>HiPay Wallet is the only solution, in Europe, that provides alternative payment solutions specific to each country, in addition to the classic bank card offer.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter" src="https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/Xo5XG4JGyLPR1kq0fCdsbRkLUALIbgCsegXdc03eoaV5f2RV2dAY3rHrf6pw2x981BFH_6zzwbPwwOzEmj80788ZgjlBThuAqcU7taLC-cyEQQX-XPkg86oXzFANuxyK6w" alt="" width="195px;" height="113px;" /><br />
HiPay constantly works and negotiates with banks, to be able to offer all the payments solutions that are used across Europe.</p>
<p>You can now allow your customers to purchase more easily and pay with their preferred payment options: bank transfers, cash payments, pre-authorized bank withdrawals, debit and credit card.</p>
<p><strong>Below, an overview of some of the options available through HiPay Wallet</strong>:</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter" src="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/pmSMlDH_l8TN-e4cKnfw8y-x51FKFyGkCFLCOBHvlv1_p4HYNosRgjGlHs5sk_qcCFAbaABIEVUgN6ZZTRreh9Npbm6sjIC2ydd28bNQN6muGCupimEjBeJVCV2-wwOBQA" alt="" width="426px;" height="332px;" /></p>
<p><a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/en/payments-gateways-prestashop-modules/1746-hipay.html" target="_blank">HiPay’s module</a> is available for the following countries: <strong>France, Belgium, Switzerland, United Kingdom, Spain, Italy, Netherlands, Germany, Portugal, Norway, Poland, Romania and the Czech Republic</strong>. The module is native in the software – for versions 1.5 and 1.6. Alternatively, it can be downloaded for free on <strong>PrestaShop’s Official Marketplace</strong>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/ecommerce-must-have-payment-methods-in-europe/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>5</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ecommerce Design: How to Find the Right Logo for Your Online Store</title>
		<link>http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/ecommerce-design-how-to-find-the-right-logo-for-your-online-store/</link>
		<comments>http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/ecommerce-design-how-to-find-the-right-logo-for-your-online-store/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 15 May 2014 15:26:30 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Julie Liu</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Tips and Advice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=17240</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Finding the right logo for your online store is one of the most important decisions you’ll make as an online merchant. As legendary Logo Designer Paul Rand says, “A logo is a flag, a signature… a street sign.” Your logo &#8230; <a href="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/ecommerce-design-how-to-find-the-right-logo-for-your-online-store/" rel="nofollow" class="more-link">Read more<span class="meta-nav"></span></a>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Finding the right logo for your online store is one of the most important decisions you’ll make as an online merchant. As legendary Logo Designer <a href="http://www.lifeclever.com/paul-rand-thoughts-and-despair-on-logo-design/" target="_blank">Paul Rand</a> says, “A logo is a flag, a signature… a street sign.” Your logo should clearly define your business model for your target audience. With so many options and possibilities for logo designs, where should you start?</p>
<p>Today we’re sharing tips on how to find the right logo for your online store. We’ll start with 5 qualities to look for, then share examples of powerful logos from live PrestaShop Stores, and finish with valuable resources to help you find your perfect logo.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-17241" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/05/EN_ECOMMERCE-DESIGN.jpg" alt="" width="580" height="250" /></p>
<p><span id="more-17240"></span></p>
<h2><span style="color: #008080">5 Q</span><span style="color: #008080">ualities You’ll Find in the Right Logo</span></h2>
<h4>1) Memorable and Unique</h4>
<p>our logo should visually convey features that set your company apart from the competition. It should also make a strong and lasting impression – something that customers can also easily recall. With that said, your logo should also be unique and not resemble another company’s logo too closely to avoid confusion.</p>
<h4>2) Appropriate</h4>
<p>Finding the appropriate logo is a 2 step process. First it should <strong>accurately describe your brand</strong>. Then ensure that message is conveyed to your <strong>target customer</strong>.</p>
<h4>3) Timeless</h4>
<p>Ensure your logo is timeless by not relying too heavily on trends. Not sure what design trends are? Think stylistic designs like gradients, transparent layers, and futuristic fonts that were popular a few years ago. See what they look with examples of 2008’s Design Trends from <a href="http://www.logoorange.com/logo-design-08.php" target="_blank">LogoOrange</a>.</p>
<h4>4) Properly Colored</h4>
<p>We naturally associate colors with ideas and feelings. Get the most out of your logo by using colors that represents your brand. According to <a href="https://99designs.com/launch/brand-identity-pack/7ac5d0fd8f00bb21/brief" target="_blank">99Designs</a>, some common association of color in Western Culture are:</p>
<p><span style="color: #ffffff">.</span>          <span style="color: #ff0000"><strong>Red</strong></span>: Passion, Anger, Vigor, Love, Danger<br />
<span style="color: #ffffff">.</span>          <span style="color: #ff9900"><strong>Orange:</strong></span> Creativity, Invigoration, Unique, Stimulation<br />
<span style="color: #ffffff">.</span>          <span style="color: #e4c547"><strong>Yellow:</strong></span> Knowledge, Energy, Joy, Intellect, Youth<br />
<span style="color: #ffffff">.</span>          <span style="color: #339966"><strong>Green:</strong></span> Fertility, Wealth, Healing, Success, Growth<br />
<span style="color: #ffffff">.</span>          <span style="color: #0000ff"><strong>Blue:</strong></span> Knowledge, Trust, Tranquility, Calm, Peace, Cool<br />
<span style="color: #ffffff">.</span>          <span style="color: #993399"><strong>Purple:</strong></span> Royalty, Wisdom, Spirituality, Imagination<br />
<span style="color: #ffffff">.</span>          <span style="color: #ffffff;background-color: #000000"><strong>White:</strong></span> Purity, Healing, Perfection, Clean, Virtue<br />
<span style="color: #ffffff">.</span>          <span style="color: #999999"><strong>Gray:</strong></span> Balance, Sophistication, Neutrality, Uncommitted<br />
<span style="color: #ffffff">.</span>          <span style="color: #000000"><strong>Black:</strong></span>Fear, Secrecy, Formal, Luxury</p>
<p>Do not, however, rely solely on color for effect. Make sure your logo also works in black and white.</p>
<h4>5) Simple and Clear</h4>
<p>Logos are meant to be an easy way for customers to remember your company. Show your logo to a stranger for 10 seconds. Did they get a good idea of your brand and company from the logo? If not, simplify the design. Stick to no more than 2 types of unscripted fonts. Then, remove any unnecessary designs.</p>
<h2><span style="color: #008080">Let’s Get Technical</span></h2>
<p><span style="color: #ffffff">.</span>          • <span style="color: #000000"><strong>Use vector images.</strong></span> These types of images are created with mathematical equations which allows them to be scaled small or large without pixelating. According to <a href="http://www.olypress.com/vector-vs-raster-graphics-in-printing/" target="_blank">Olympus Press</a>, “crisp edges” are the most important aspect of a logo. Vector images will ensure your logo keeps its crisp edges.</p>
<p><span style="color: #ffffff">.</span>          • <span style="color: #000000"><strong>Create logos in varying sizes.</strong></span> Your logo should be consistent across all areas of your online store. However, it may not always fit into the specified dimensions. Take for example the various default sizes for the different logos placements within PrestaShop. (Easily edit these from the Back Office &gt; Preferences &gt; Themes.)<br />
<span style="color: #ffffff">.</span>           <span style="color: #ffffff"> </span>         o Header Logo (350px X 99px)<br />
<span style="color: #ffffff">.</span>       <span style="color: #ffffff">    </span>          o Favicon (16px X 16px)<br />
<span style="color: #ffffff">.</span>           <span style="color: #ffffff"> </span>         o Store Icon (30px X 30X)<br />
<span style="color: #ffffff">.</span>          • <span style="color: #000000"><strong>Create versions for different print mediums</strong></span>. Letter heads, business cards, envelopes, as well as advertising posters are just a few other places you might use your logo. Make sure you have a version that works with each medium you use.</p>
<h2><span style="color: #008080">Examples of Logos from PrestaShop Stores</span></h2>
<p>Check out these great logos! Can you guess what these PrestaShop merchants sell just from their logos?</p>
<h4 style="text-align: left"><a href="http://www.starcowparis.com/10-shop" target="_blank"><strong>Starcow Paris </strong></a><br />
<img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-17243" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/05/Starcow-Logo.jpg" alt="" width="162" height="90" /> <img class="aligncenter  wp-image-17244" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/05/StarcowImage2.jpg" alt="" width="247" height="151" /></h4>
<p><strong>Business Model:</strong> Premier Parisian retailer for streetwear with skate and hip-hop influence<br />
<strong>Why It Works:</strong> For starters, their logo is timeless. They steered clear of graffiti influence or highly styled fonts. Although the S in the logo has lots of character, it is still easy to understand. Furthermore, the scripted font reflects the prices and feel of their store; it’s refined with a little bit of edge and style.</p>
<h4><a href="http://www.yumise.com/american-gourmandises" target="_blank"><strong>Yumise</strong></a><br />
<img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-17247" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/05/Yumise-Logo.jpg" alt="" width="293" height="168" /></h4>
<p><strong>Business Model:</strong> French retailer for edible American products<br />
<strong>Why It Works:</strong> This font is relevant for food lovers yet easy to understand. They clarify their unique brand name with a clear tagline below the store name to summarize the business model. It is simple but clearly shows the brand image.</p>
<h4><strong><a href="http://printthemall.com/" target="_blank">Print Them All</a></strong></h4>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-17242" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/05/printthemall-logo.png" alt="" width="152" height="176" /><br />
<strong>Business Model:</strong> Art dealer for prints from street artist.<br />
<strong>Why It Works:</strong>The use of gray, which projects neutrality, is perfect for an art dealer. The understated logo clearly communicates their role in the art process – feature the artist. The modern use of the fountain pens also shows the rebellious side of the company. This works well to showcase how they differentiate themselves in an established business market.</p>
<h4><a href="http://www.todobonito.com/" target="_blank"><strong>Todo Bonito</strong><br />
</a></h4>
<p style="text-align: center"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-17245" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/05/todobonito1.png" alt="" width="144" height="144" /><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-17246" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/05/todobonito2.png" alt="" width="394" height="68" /></p>
<p><strong>Business Model:</strong> Downloadable cutout designs for children parties and celebrations.<br />
<strong>Why It Works:</strong> The doily pattern behind the text alludes to the products that company sells – paper with designs that can be cut out. They also have multiple logos for different size requirements. The square logo is perfect for social media profile images where the rectangular logo works well for ecommerce headers. Finally, the pink hues are perfect for their target audiences – moms planning kid parties.</p>
<p>Need more sample logos for inspiration? Check out <a href="http://www.logomoose.com/" target="_blank">LogoMoose </a>or <a href="http://www.logoorange.com/logo-design.php" target="_blank">LogoOrange</a>.</p>
<h2><span style="color: #008080">Resources for Logo Designs</span></h2>
<p>So now that you know what to look for in a logo, how do you find you own? For online stores with small budgets, <a href="http://www.fiverr.com/search/gigs?utf8=%E2%9C%93&amp;search_in=everywhere&amp;query=logo&amp;x=0&amp;y=0&amp;jls_se99912_1_auto=1" target="_blank">Fiverr </a>is a good resource with almost 20,000 different graphic designers offering their services for just $5. For more substantial budgets, consider <a href="http://99designs.com/how-it-works" target="_blank">99 designs </a>for ready-made logos starting at $99 or start a logo design contest starting from $299.</p>
<p>Already have a logo for your online store &#8211; how did you find it? Share in the comments below!</p>
<div>
<hr align="left" size="2" width="33%" />
</div>
<p>Not an online store owner yet? <a href="http://www.prestashop.com/en/demo" target="_blank">Demo PrestaShop</a> – the best ecommerce software – or get started today by <a href="http://www.prestashop.com/en/download" target="_blank">downloading</a> this online shopping cart software for free!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/ecommerce-design-how-to-find-the-right-logo-for-your-online-store/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>

<!-- Performance optimized by W3 Total Cache. Learn more: http://www.w3-edge.com/wordpress-plugins/

Minified using disk: basic
Page Caching using disk: enhanced
Object Caching 829/968 objects using disk: basic

Served from: www.prestashop.com @ 2014-06-24 03:56:02 -->